<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>a-tune-that</title>
    <link href="http://atunethat.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://atunethat.com" />
    <updated>2017-12-31T10:18:17+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Roo</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://atunethat.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title> </title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/the-year-in-review-2017.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/the-year-in-review-2017.html</id>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-31T21:26:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/30/yr.jpg" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">The Year in review</h3>
<h4>Viktor</h4>
I like New Year’s! Out of all arbitrary things we celebrate I suppose at least with the new year celebrations the randomness inherent in the tradition is pretty up-front. At some point someone decided that this would be the day when the year ends and a new one begins and at least not enough people could be arsed to disagree in any loud enough way to prevent it from spreading out in the world (after having somehow latched on to christian tradition even though the new year in of itself holds no religious significance in christianity). Of Course China, India, the muslim world and Israel all have other (sometimes just as arbitrary) dates for their new year but we all celebrate the fact that we didn’t screw up horribly enough to prevent our planet from managing to make it all the way round the sun once again. It is also a holiday focused on the future rather than the past which is clearly refreshing amongst holidays. So on that note I’ll proceed to reminisce about the year that passed... <br><br>
<div style="float: left; padding-right: 4px;"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/tunatunes/playlist/3R1RRB33aoIyLoh82ez3RH" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="float: left;">We are still a quarter shy of a full year with ATuneThat but let’s not let petty details stop us from celebrating our first year with the blog. For me it has truly been the tonic the doctor ordered. All the things I hoped to achieve has come to pass. Music has been my no. 1 interest in life as far back as I can remember. However seeing how I haven’t played in a band or worked as a DJ for over a decade and over the last few years I have been scaling back on teaching music as well, my relation to music as an active practitioner has almost completely been severed. With ATuneThat I am making myself active in relation to the music I listen to as well as rekindled the wonderful ongoing music discussion I used to have with my good friend Roobin. <br><br> 2017 has been a good year in music. It had a lot to live up to as the year before it was pretty amazing. Also, there were quite a few albums that had been long in the making or where follow-ups to great albums and thus risked having too much anticipation riding on their curtails. All in all I have to say that 2017 delivered. It will be abundantly clear to each and everyone when you look at the cheere tremendousness of the music in this; my year end playlist.</div>
Roobin and I approach music from slightly different angles but somehow we end up in very similar places. This is evident ofcourse in our writing but also in silly small details such as the fact that I have 52 songs in my one list for the year while Roobin has made four lists of 21 songs each. I went with 52 since that is a full deck of cards and I just bet that Roobin at least thought about the card game Blackjack (or 21 as it is commonly known in Sweden) when he picked his number. In perhaps a less subtle contrast, Robbin's playlists are all thematic collections of songs to be enjoyed in any order while I have composed one playlist much like a DJ-set with a beginning and a carefully drawn path through to the end. For me the individual tracks of an album or indeed a good playlist are made more significant when put in the right context. This thinking extends to the whole blog for me. In choosing a tune for a challenge as well as with the accompanying texts, I hope to build a new context in which to enjoy the songs I pic. This way I hope that our readers but more significantly; I, will re-discover or sometimes even actually discover the music I have chosen. <br><br> Oh and on an important side note; I did my part to try and get Sun Parade’s Shuggy Mtn Breakdown on our Top 10 List but it wasn't to be as someone gave it the second lowest possible score, I bet that someone has a case of the remorse blues. <br><br> So finally, in looking forward to 2018. <br> It has been a great joy and very much something I hadn’t anticipated, that so many of the artists we write about would taken the time to read the articles. I cannot wish for anything better than to have this continue into the coming year. <br><br> For next year I also really really wish to get our regular readers more involved in the discussions I and Roobin so enjoy. I do not know what we can do to get you, our dear readers, to feel more involved but I sure ame to find out. <br><br> So let's get on with it, let’s get on with 2018! <br><br>
<h4>Roobin</h4>
One of the best things that happened this year was the decision to start this blog together with my good friend Viktor. On the first of May we posted our first challenge and after that we have continued with the challenges every other week and it stills feels as fun as that first time. Some challenges have been harder than others, “...once hated but now love” - comes to mind as one of the toughest. The hunt for tunes has, without a doubt, been the most fun part. Scrobbling thru song after song late at night; to find that perfect tune has been a lot of fun. <br><br>
<div style="float: left;">This blog we have is mainly for our own amusement and we never thought that we would attract the masses, though I thought that we would get a few more reader than what we have, but we have good hopes for the future. We have gotten positive feedback from several artist which is super awesome and gives us fuel to write even better. My engrish has improved a tiny bit, but I still struggle with that natural flow. That's something to improve in 2018. <br><br> I have 245 songs clocking in at 14 hours and 9 minutes in my playlist for the year. I do save everything that I find interesting in that list, so it’s only natural for it to be long. I’ve managed to narrow it down to <a href="https://open.spotify.com/user/roobine/playlist/6sjlvR2BDvhaRHRyyjxy0d" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a list of 100</a>. For your sake, but mostly mine, I have in addition to that splitted the hundred to more manageable chunks of 21 tunes, four bite sized list in total. Why that odd number 21? Well it’s to compensate, and make amends for not throwing ourselves at the altar of Sun Parade, as we should have. The compensation is that they get one tune on each of the list, well deserved of course. Shuggy Mtn Breakdown is a first class album that should have been on our top list. I nominated it but then failed to give it the points it deserved. The four lists each has a theme, and what tune belongs to what list is a secret that only I know (and sometimes even I am baffled over the decisions).</div>
<div style="clear: both;"> </div>
List one: <a href="https://open.spotify.com/user/roobine/playlist/0Uq1z1Xiex2QM7RfmK9kNb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2017, you’re so scruffy</a><br>This is where I’ve put the tunes that you need to pick you up a dark tuesday morning. Bring out your air guitar and start stomping your feet. If you got a safety pin stuck in your heart, this is the list for you.<br><iframe width="300" height="70" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/roobine/playlist/0Uq1z1Xiex2QM7RfmK9kNb" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe><br><br> List two: <a href="https://open.spotify.com/user/roobine/playlist/0UEIZR1acq0SYda3PhjLvj">2017, you’re so tuneful</a><br> The list for the sing along tunes that never seems to leave your head. Works for occasions when you just want some well crafted tunes that makes you feel good to the bone. Clear your throat, time to sing along.<br><iframe width="300" height="70" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/roobine/playlist/0UEIZR1acq0SYda3PhjLvj" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe> <br><br>List three: <a href="https://open.spotify.com/user/roobine/playlist/2n0uaG29KKJo6r7bpKXD45">2017, you’re so smooth</a><br> A list where the low key, smooth, down tempo tunes get to live. When you need to wind down or you just feel for something calmer to lean your weary ears against - put on this smooth playlist and just relax.<br><iframe width="300" height="70" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/roobine/playlist/2n0uaG29KKJo6r7bpKXD45" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe> <br><br> List four: <a href="https://open.spotify.com/user/roobine/playlist/1Cp4TTWXRFNUlD7SHUmnXf">2017, you’re so retro</a><br> Sometimes you just need that smell of vinyl, and 2017 had a lot of great tunes with that nostalgic odeur. Many genres, different moods and sounds crowd together on this great list that is perfect for the times when your ears want to something it recognises but your mind wants something fresh.<br> <iframe width="300" height="70" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/roobine/playlist/1Cp4TTWXRFNUlD7SHUmnXf" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<div style="clear: both;"> </div>
The full List<br>
<div><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/roobine/playlist/6sjlvR2BDvhaRHRyyjxy0d" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<h3>…and for our next task, we will find a tune that…</h3>
<h5>..makes me excited about an album announced to be released in 2018</h5>
A brand new year comes with the promise of brand new releases of course. Some artists have been teasing or otherwise testing the waters with singles, EPs or just some tune for streaming to get the hype roling. Well what has caught our eye and peaked our curiosity or just plain hooked us up with an addiction feveroulsy needing more. <br><br> Be sure to check back January the 14th when our first challenge of the the year will be finished!
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title> A tune that is great for christmas</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/is-great-for-christmas.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/is-great-for-christmas.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-25T15:46:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/28/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">A tune that is great for christmas</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">Half of us loves christmas tunes and one half loathes them. This playlist is as much for the Hater half as it is for the rest of you. It it simply put the best christmas playlist ever put together and is a honest try to pierce the heart of the other half of us with the spear of christmas tune love. <br><br> The journey begins with Moto Boy's magical version of Ave Maria, and what follows is a string of classic cozy christmas tunes. The list might be a bit heavy on the jazz side, but then again can that side really be to heavy? The name of the king of christmas tunes ain't Bing, Elvis or Shane, it's not even a king; it's a queen and her name is Ella. The wonderful Ella Fitzgerald found her way into the list with quite a lot of songs, as it should be. No christmas is complete without Jussi singing O Helga Natt(O holy night) for everything he is worth - pure gold, so he gets to wrap up this fantastic playlist. <br><br> Treat yourself with something good to drink, sit yourself down in a comfy chair and enjoy these mood enhancing carrols (that goes for you to, Hater). <br><br> Merry christmas and God Jul!</div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="600" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/roobine/playlist/0bYD7EexajNa03ImBMCH4Y" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;">&nbsp;</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top albums 2017 #1</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-cende-no1-hit-single.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-cende-no1-hit-single.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-24T16:22:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/27/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Cende - #1 Hit Single</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">In Swedish we have a saying “Underbart är kort”. It roughly translates to Bliss is Brief. I seem to recall a proverb or some such about flames burning bright but it slipped my mind and I can’t be arsed to look it up. Just as instantly as we fell in love with Cende’s stellar album #1 Hit Single, with just that same instantaneous transition, our hearts fell with grief. We hadn’t even gotten enough time to properly profess our love before we learned that the band was to cease to exist. Luckily #1 Hit Single will last forever. It is eternally good and profoundly wonderful. Indi pop perfection. Simply the very best album of the year.<br> </div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="480" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/5OY1zwQHzgkqVrJczvikNg" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;"> </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top tunes 2017 #1</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-dan-luke-nad-the-raid-golden-age.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-dan-luke-nad-the-raid-golden-age.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-23T17:03:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/26/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Dan Luke and the Raid - Golden Age</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">Golden Age is more than just a tune. It’s practically a whole album’s worth of music crammed inside the confines of one single and mind you, very coherent, tune. In of itself that is no small feat. Then, if all of that musical material happens to be A-grade plutonium, absolutely lethal on mere exposure ...well then you know you might have the no.1 tune of the year on your hands. Dan Luke and the Raid performs Golden Age with a lot of playfulness but at the same time with a nerve and sincerity that would perhaps feel contradictory from lesser artists or in a merely great tune. This tune however has the chopps to contain and shelter us from any amount of excellence-rays. All evidence points to the conclusion that Golden Age is infact a real-life-superhero who is, right now as I’m typing this, saving the earth from...<br> </div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/6xawr2pyZcq76wTW7SHJrQ" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;"> </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top albums 2017 #2</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-sinkane-life-living-it.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-sinkane-life-living-it.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-22T16:59:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/25/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Sinkane - Life &amp; Living It</h3>
<h3 class="align-center"> </h3>
<div class="posttext">Boy do I have sumthin’ sumthin’ for you, so we’ve been sitting on this stash of purified uncut contraband joy, all conveniently pressed into 180 gram black virgin vinyl slabs or if you so prefer lil’ shiny ‘bout 5 inch sized plastic discs, heck if you rather have it completely digitally we could have that arranged as well, whatever floats your boat. Sinkane floats our boats, cars and locomotives. <br><br> Fusing soul, funk and disco with african music such as high life is nothing new of course but the raw and uncompromising sound and attitude of Fela Kuti always placed his music well clear of pop. Osibisa sometimes tried to approach pop music but never this effortlessly. Life &amp; Living it is however much more than just a pop afrobeat record, so much more. Like on first hearing Telephone we had to double check that we hadn’t gotten it all wrong all our lives but no, the Bee Gees do suck, it’s just Sinkane wielding some kind of weird magic and getting away with that sort of sound. <br><br> Be warned! there is not one single tune on this record that isn’t highly addictive.<br> </div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/1c3KGWogY8wW9LN7MuYcp2" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;"> </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top tunes 2017 #2</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-jason-isbell-if-we-were-vampires.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-jason-isbell-if-we-were-vampires.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-21T16:54:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/24/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Jason Isbell - If We Were Vampires</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">Be it by chance or design but apparently sometimes even the Grammy jury get it right. This is however the only instance where anything on our lists have been nominated for a grammy this year; much outrage, very sad wow. Seriously though, This tune is profoundly philosophical as well as gut wrenchingly sad while also surprisingly warm. Inspiringly optimistic while terminally dark, gentle yet brutal. However most importantly it is epicly beautiful.<br> </div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/250RLekaiL1q9qZer975Eg" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;"> </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top albums 2017 #3</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-elder-reflections-of-a-floataing-world.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-elder-reflections-of-a-floataing-world.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-20T16:51:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/23/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Elder - Reflections of a Floating World</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">The first encounter with Reflections of a Floating World can be a real thriller. Two bars into the first track of Reflections it&rsquo;s settled, This is awesome! ...people talk about love at first sight but that is very scary. Will the feeling be reciprocated. In this case; will the album or atleast the tune be able to sustain this initial greatness? As the opening track Sanctuary thunders on it becomes more an more clear that oh man you can bet on it, and then as track after track on the record twists and turns their way through bars upon bars of ever more labyrinthian riffs, all initial promises are fulfilled. This is the third best album of the year. Don&rsquo;t worry it is just as good as it seems.<br><br></div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/15yxKj4XCoCfSVJsgRjZQt" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;">&nbsp;</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top tunes 2017 #3</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-sweet-years-fireproof.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-sweet-years-fireproof.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-19T16:44:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/22/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Sweet years - Fireproof</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">We have already covered the album on our album list, but there is one tune on it that deserves some extra attention. &ldquo;I'm tired of being people with you motherfuckers!&rdquo; - is an already classic line, in our minds. The main part, the awesome punk tune, of the song is over by the minute mark and then an equally awesome outro takes over. It does not conform and it is so splendid that it's in the top three. At #3 it&rsquo;s Sweet Years - Fireproof! <em>Perfection, perfection, perfection, perfection, perfection, perfection, perfection!</em><br>&nbsp;</div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/0cDkNkmgdqyi5EtVB0yfxJ" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;">&nbsp;</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top albums 2017 #4</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-mounika-how-are-you.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-albums-2017-mounika-how-are-you.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-18T20:37:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/21/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Mounika - How Are You</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">Mounika has created an almost unique soundscape on this tremendous album. He deconstructs sounds and rebuilds them, the outcome is a lovely trip. It&rsquo;s not only the sound he plays with, it&rsquo;s also our nostalgia and our brains little safe place. It&rsquo;s a little like coming home. Cut My Hair could easily have been on our tunes list, but the album is so good it deserves it&rsquo;s place here. Mounika - How Are You is our 4th best album this year, with this fantastic chill-hop album.</div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/6Lyjbk8BJ0LyXkd7V70tUV" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;">&nbsp;</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Top tunes 2017 #4</title>
        <author>
            <name>ATuneThat</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-otoboke-beaver-mean.html"/>
        <id>http://atunethat.com/top-tunes-2017-otoboke-beaver-mean.html</id>
            <category term="Yule Calendar"/>
            <category term="2017"/>

        <updated>2017-12-17T20:33:00+01:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://atunethat.com/media/posts/20/julkalender.png" alt="" />
                <h3 class="align-center">Otoboke Beaver - Mean</h3>
<br>
<div class="posttext">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dennis Leary has this famous quote; &ldquo;Happiness comes in small doses folks. It's a cigarette butt, or a chocolate chip cookie or a five second orgasm. You come, you smoke the butt you eat the cookie you go to sleep wake up and go back to fucking work the next morning, THAT'S IT! End of fucking list!&rdquo;.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We would humbly ask to change the list slightly: &ldquo;... It&rsquo;s a chocolate chip cookie or a five second orgasm or a 19 sec punk tune from Otoboke Beaver.&rdquo;. Now, that&rsquo;s it, end of fucking list!</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mic drop.</span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also we love them, they can very well be the coolest band around. Please come to sweden!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 4th best tune this year, will have you screaming for more!</span></p>
</div>
<div class="spotifyembed"><iframe width="300" height="380" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/1cWr2uUUxHHUsIe1ynDflP" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div style="clear: both;">&nbsp;</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
